Taylor Reese

9242 Settlers Grove Rd. • Covington, GA • 30014 • Tel: 770.314.4734 • E-mail: Taylor.reesel@outlook.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Project Manager, District Manager and Customer Engagement Leader with over 6 years of expertise performing as a customer relationship management (CRM) expert for leading global organizations (i.e., Aldi), Fortune 500 corporations (i.e., QuikTrip), and government entities. Responsible for the strategy, development and success of new client accounts for major corporations. Provide oversight, coordination and direction for the ongoing systematic evaluation of project deliverables, program management and business operations. Repeated success guiding sizeable, cross-functional teams in the design and launch of programs, contract negotiations and client/vendor relationship management. Successfully combines tactical execution of strategic initiatives to capture and enhance overall quality, improved customer experience and performance improvement.

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY of GEORGIA, Athens, Georgia Bachelor of Business Administration, BBA Concentration: Management

05/2012

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALDI, Jefferson, Georgia District Manager

08/2016 - Present

Construct value and gain unique company-wide leadership experience through year-long training program by co-managing over 4 stores with 100+ employees. Explore and define opportunities, set sales strategy, and create tangible project management designs. Evaluate sales initiatives through consumer research, competitive/trends analysis and the creation of internal metrics and management reporting.

- Perform work as part of an integrated managerial operational team (e.g., District Managers and Senior Managers)
 conducting analysis and providing recommendations in the areas of risk management and business priority generation.
- Maintain product knowledge and effective selling skills in order to influence customers and targeted accounts.
- Develop strong B2B relationships concerning merchandising metrics with category projections, net contribution by style and SKUs, and advise on replenishment opportunities for generating future sales.
- Champion key process metrics in soundness, profitability, growth, and productivity for key consumer segments impacting positive client experiences.

QUIKTRIP, Conyers, Georgia Assistant Manager

01/2014 - 08/2016

Exercised the full range of supervisory management responsibilities which included determining priority projects and assessing records and financial data for over \$18M in sales annually. Managed 15 direct reports and oversaw staff operations, business planning and budget development. Ensured all personnel completed onboarding training tasks and maintained new hire requirements. Built high-performance sales and customer service teams and retained top talent to drive business goals.

- Supported budgeting processes and tracking to provide more effective business decision-making.
- Monitored the performance of all phases of inventory control systems and operations including receiving, stocking, disbursement, returns, and cycle counting while meeting designated standards for shrinkage and loss.

Taylor Reese • Tel: 770.314.4734 • E-mail: Taylor.reese1@outlook.com

Page 1

- Accountable for the development and performance of overall growth strategy for company's portfolios including business development, acquisition, and the execution of new business channels.
- Conducted trend analyses to identify areas where additional customer training and assistance was needed and initiated appropriate actions such as defining new operational requirements.

Special Projects Team

Managed, oversaw, and implemented merchandising strategies to achieve and drive category performance for entry into new market territories. Spearheaded strategic product planning for Quiktrip's vendor brands, consumer research, sales/expense planning, and promotion analysis. Oversaw sales performance and identified sales trends, analyzed sales results, and anticipated needs of the business.

- Provided feedback while managing overall project portfolio, cost projections, profitability, and risk management.
- Gathered technical data to evaluate potential areas to provide comprehensive recommendations for project management and incremental delivery growth.
- Implemented comprehensive audit strategies to oversee, track and evaluate the effectiveness of project compliance.
- Oversaw deliverables, methodology, quality of client engagement, and the coordination of sales programs in support of tactical objectives.

JW BUSINESS ACQUISITIONS, Atlanta, Georgia

09/2013 - 01/2014

Account Manager and Corporate Trainer

Provided oversight management of \$450,000 in sales, resulting in award-winning territory performance for including consistently being ranked in top 15% percentile of sales representatives nationwide. Oversaw the cultivation of relationships with Key Opinion Leaders (KOLs). Generated over 30 new customer acquisitions within first month of employment

- Ascertained business opportunities and risks through creating growth strategies by defining offerings and advancing
 partnerships through marketing products for several key accounts.
- Managed staff members and all phases of projects covering concurrent work streams.
- Delivered product presentations to customers in territory outlining products, features, benefits, and services.
- Exceeded all business measurements, including sales activity, pipeline development, and quota achievement.

ATHENS CLARKE COUNTY UNIFIED GOVERNMENT, Athens, Georgia

08/2010 - 09/2013

Park Assistant

Charged with managing staff, program and objectives to ensure the delivery of high quality park services. Oversaw the planning and implementation of strategies while achieving short and long-term operational goals. Managed a daily budget for program operations and achieved revenue goals. Developed guidance and resource documents.

- Supported budgeting processes and tracking to provide more effective business decision-making.
- Implemented changes to drive further refinements of operational processes and policies for community access.
- Planned and implemented parks and recreational programs in collaboration with local and various public/non-profit organizations which increased participation by 20%.

CHIME GLOBAL CONSULTING, Athens, Georgia

08/2011 - 05/2012

Intern

Assisted with the implementation of corporate solutions across multiple stakeholders focusing on strategic program planning, recruitment, sponsorships, and stakeholder engagement. Consulted over 4 corporations to improve relationships through establishing open communication with clients, corporate sponsors and cooperating agencies. Served as liaison successfully acquiring over \$5,000 in corporate sponsorships to host annual networking gala.

• Co-led the organization and execution of business planning and training programs for **300** participants by providing leadership support, advisement, evaluation, and the successful implementation of business procedures and policies.

Taylor Reese • Tel: 770.314.4734 • E-mail: <u>Taylor.reese1@outlook.com</u>

- Conducted project status briefings and sponsorship strategy updates to agency director for project awareness, feedback, and adoption of strategy methodology and work products.
- Utilized audience-base marketing data (Strategy and Analytics) to manage the implementation of appropriate and effective campaign materials reaching over **20,000** of individuals yearly.